Edmund "Eddie" Howard

1016 Garfield St. 443-834-5445 Madison, Wisconsin 53711 ehoward2@wisc.edu

Objective

Secure an opportunity contributing to a team while gaining practical experience and scientific knowledge in the fields of geology and geographic information systems.

Skills/ Knowledge

I have acquired public interaction skills, discipline, teamwork, outdoor and interpersonal experience while maintaining a safe and fun environment for tourists and co-workers aboard a vessel. I received training in CPR/AED, First Aid and boating. I have extensive wilderness knowledge and flexibility to adapt to changing circumstances. I have developed public speaking, leadership, patience and management skills through multiple leadership positions and training conferences.

Education

2016 – 2018 University of Wisconsin - Madison, Madison, WI.

Bachelor of Science (Expected December 2020) Geology, Cartography and Geographic

Information Systems, GPA: 3.1.

Courses include: Mineralogy, Petrology, Geologic History of the Earth, Introduction to Geologic

Structures, Introduction to Cartography, and Geobiology.

Relevant Experience

June-July 2018 Wasatch-Uinta Field Camp, Park City, UT.

Worked in many field environments doing activities such as geologic mapping, cross section

drawing, stratigraphic column creation, rock descriptions, and other field related activities.

June-August 2016 Lab Assistant, United States Geological Survey, Baltimore, MD.

Cleaned lab equipment, prepared lab experiments and organized data.

General Experience

June- August 2019 Line Cook and Cashier, Sett Pub, Madison, WI.

Worked as part of a team to effectively serve customers food and drinks under the supervision of supervisors and managers. Used food safety and general safety knowledge to care for customers

and members of the team.

June-August 2017 Deckhand, Baltimore Water Taxi, Baltimore, MD.

Acted as junior safety officer of the vessel under a captain's command, with additional responsibilities of docking, embarking, ticketing and disembarking. Responsible for health and welfare of the passengers and provided customer service, including ticket transactions, for tourists

and commuters while on board the vessel.

2012 - 2015 National Youth Leadership Training Staff, Baltimore Area Council, Boy Scouts of America,

Baltimore, MD.

Managed a staff, prepared presentations, taught participant leadership skills. Positions included

Senior Patrol Leader, Assistant Senior Patrol Leader of Program and Service.

<u>Certifications</u> Leave No Trace, CPR/AED, First Aid.

Technical Skills Computer proficiency including Microsoft Word, Power Point, Email and Internet. ArcGIS,

Python (1 year), ENVI, Adobe Photoshop, Mapbox Studio and Adobe Illustrator.

Awards/ Honors 2016 U.S. Marine Corps Semper Fidelis Award; 2016 John Philip Sousa Award; 2015 Eagle Scout,

Boy Scouts of America.

Memberships 2017-2018 University of Wisconsin Marching & Varsity Bands, 2009-2016 Member Boy Scouts

of America.